这是我的简历
Here's my resume.
严格来说  叫"学术简历"
I mean, technically it says "curriculum vitae,"
虽然这么叫会更专业点  不过
Which I think is more professional, but,
其实两个都差不多的
You know, same thing pretty much.
有简历倒是不错  不过这个岗位其实
That's...wow. Great. But this position truly is
不太需要什么工作经验
A no-experience-necessary kind of things.
虽然简历里没有写到
Well, and it doesn't really say it here,
不过我在销售方面很有背景优势
But I have a solid background in sales.
我做事很主动的
I'm pretty much a self-starter, so.
-很不错  但是  -不错
- That's excellent, but...  - Excellent. I just...
我觉得我可以成为
I really feel I could be a major,
您销售团队中的主力
Major asset to your sales force.
我想可能有点小误会
I'm thinking there's a little misunderstanding.
这其实不是真正意义上的销售
This isn't actually a sales job.
我很乐意考虑你担任销售
I mean, I'd be happy to consider you for a sales position,
但是我们的员工需要有资格证
But our agents need to be licensed,
至少两年的相关工作经验
Have at least two years on-the-job experience,
而且一般是本科毕业
And usually a college degree.
你更适合的工作应该是
What you would be doing is more like...
广告类
Advertising.
你好啊  杰西
Hey, Jesse!
嘿  哥们
Hey, man!
等一下  哥们  怎么了
Yo, man! What up?
猴子
Badger?
最近都在哪混啊
Where you been keeping yourself?
行头不错嘛
Nice duds.
你的也不赖啊
Yeah. You, too.
谢谢
Thanks.
你为什么要干这么傻的工作
Yo, why would you want to do this lame ass job anyway?
别误会  我无意冒犯
I mean, no offense.
因为我在服缓刑
Because I'm on probation, yo.
需要证明自己已经改过自新
Gotta prove to the man I'm rehabilitated.
成为正直的公民  都是那种屁话
Upstanding citizen. All that shit.
不过也算是很好的锻炼
It's really good exercise, too.
你不能光站在那
Look. You can't just stand there.
还得旋转箭头
You have to spin the arrow.
像直升机的动作  这些你都得学
There's all these moves you have to learn, like a helicopter.
看到了吗
See?
这个动作比较难
That one's a bitch.
我还不太熟练
I'm not very good at it yet.
不  你真的让我大开眼界了
No, you really opened my eyes to the possibilities.
不管怎么说
Hey, anyways...
-谢谢借我抽一口  -要抽找我就是
- Thanks for the toke.  - Anytime.
说起这个
Speaking of which...
你能不能给我弄点冰毒
You think you could maybe hook me up with some crystal?
不行  我已经金盆洗手很久了
Nah, I've been out of the business for a while.
-其实我正打算隐退  -什么  不是吧
- Actually now thinking about retiring.  - What? No!
你做的货难以置信
That stuff you made is unbelievable.
那确实是相当棒
It was pretty awesome.
隐退
Retirement?
我没听错吧
I can't be hearing this!
我有一个搭档在帮我制毒
I had this partner who was helping me cook.
其实主要是我在出力  不过
I mean, I was doing most of the work, but...
他是个混蛋  所以
He was an asshole, so...
光顾的买家也就越来越少了
Anyway, pseudo's getting harder and harder to come by.
我可以帮你介绍买家
No, I can hook you up with some pseudo.
大买家
Major pseudo.
哥们  我可是有渠道的
I got channels, bro.
我们可以合伙
We could partner up.
不要有压力
No pressure. No pressure.
你就考虑下  好吗
Just think about it, all right?
该死  我得走了
Oh shit.
我得走了
I gotta go.
储蓄所往这边走咯
Yo, this way to savings!
能帮你省钱啊
Save your dollar bills, yo!
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
都来存点钱吧
Come on, save some money.
翻译：诺米    壹壹    小松狮    Marvin    夜
■
时间轴：虫不知    傻蛐蛐     特效：Will
绝
命
毒
师
第一季
第五集
校对：冰卡      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
好傻的礼物
It's a stupid gift.
不会的  他会喜欢的
No, it isn't. He'll love it.
我都不知道自己怎么做的思考
I don't know what I was thinking.
请帖上不是说"不要送礼"吗
Didn't the invitation even say "no gifts"?
-沃尔特  -又怎么啦
- Walt. - What?
我们一定要去的
We have to go.
我知道  我这不是抱怨
I know. I'm not complaing.
你就是在抱怨
Yes, you are.
听着  我们要去的
Look, we need this.
最近经历了太多事情  知道吗
We've been through a lot lately, okay?
天哪
Jesus.
我们好久没参加这样的派对了
Guess we didn't get the beige memo.
没事
We're okay.
我像是穿着1985年款礼服的怪人
Yes, I look like I'm wearing a prom dress from 1985.
亲爱的  你看起来很不错
Honey, you look fine.
沃尔特  这是我找到的唯一一件合身的
Walt, this is the only thing I could find that fit me.
你看那里  请帖上竟然写"不要送礼"
Would you look at that? The invitation said "no gifts."
别这样
Oh, come on.
先生  我帮您收起来吧
Sir, I'll take that for you.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
快看  埃利奥特在那
Oh, look, there's Elliott.
我们过去打声招呼
Let's go say hello.
埃利奥特
Elliott.
沃尔特  你终于来啦
Walt! You made it.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
-怎么可能不来呢  -谢谢  斯凯勒
- Wouldn't miss it for the world.  - Thank you. Skyler.
是这样的
Oh, that's right.
见到你真高兴  你还是那么漂亮
Great to see you. You look beautiful as always.
这段时间  肚子变大了  不过
Well, these days a little more big than beautiful, but...
当然  恭喜你啦
Of course! Congratulations.
这真是个好消息
That was such great news.
谢谢
Thank you.
格蕾琴  看看谁来了
Gretchen, look who's here!
好久不见
It's been ages.
见到你真高兴
It's so good to see you.
真得很高兴
It's... really good.
斯凯勒  欢迎你  恭喜啦
Skyler, welcome. Congratulations.
谢谢  很高兴能来参加
Thank you. It's really nice to be here.
你的产期是什么时候
When are you due?
大概还要10周
We're looking at about ten more weeks.
其实  我们已经知道怀的是女孩
Actually, we recently found out that it's a girl.
-恭喜  -太棒了
- Congratulations. - That's so wonderful.
我们也打算要一个女孩
We've been thinking about it for ourselves.
是啊  正在考虑
Yeah, thinking about it.
顺便说下
By the way,
保护专利那个事很棒
Securing that patent was just amazing.
我是说  你的公司所做出的努力
I mean, the work that your company is doing...
恭喜你们两位
Congratulations, to both of you.
努力工作  还有常交好运
Hard work and a lot of luck.
-常交好运  -不是吧
- A lot of luck.  - Oh, well, no.
不好意思  我们要过去打招呼
Will you excuse us? We gotta say hi.
你们请随意  我们一会再聊
Make yourselves at home. We'll catch up later.
-当然  -好的
- Sure. - Okay.
-你们能来真是太好了  -谢谢
- So good you're here. - Thank you.
来吧
Shall we?
沃尔特
Walt?
果然没认错
I thought that was you.
法利
Farley!
好久不见
Long time no see.
这是沃尔特·怀特
This Walter White.
在大学的时候  他是...
Back at cal tech, he was...
你简直就是结晶学大师
You were just the master of crystallography.
我记得有一次  我们
I remember this one time, we were
在一个蛋白质问题上卡了好几个礼拜
Stuck on this protein problems for weeks!
你不过就看了眼
You just breezed right in
然后对我们说了一个词
And you had one word for us, too.
-同步加速器  -没错  同步加速器
- Synchrotrons. - It was synchrotrons, yeah.
他们在X射线下能做生成
They generate purer and more
更完美更高纯度的晶态
Complete patterns in X-ray beams.
之前的只不过是写数据收集工作
Data collection takes a fraction of the time.
怀特可是格雷麦特命名者之一
This is the White in Gray Matter.
告诉他们  沃尔特
Tell 'em, Walt.
好
Okay.
早先我们还在研究生院的时候
Well, back when Elliott and I were in grad school,
艾略特和我想出这个名字
We came up with the name.
简写成布莱克  沃尔特·怀特[黑色+白色]
Short, Black, Walter·White.
这就是格雷麦特科技的由来[灰色公司]
So, together they became Gray Matter technologies.
-可爱吧  -你和埃利奥特是合伙人么
- Cute, huh? - So you run the company with Elliott?
不  那是格蕾琴和埃利奥特
Well, no, no, that's Gretchen and Elliott.
我更倾向于教育方面
I gravitated toward education.
在哪所大学
What university?
电吉他
It's a stratocaster!
不光光是电吉他
Not just any strat.
这可是克莱普顿的
That's one of Clapton's.
不会吧
No way.
敬埃利奥特
"To elliott.
不好意思皮扣有点松  埃里克·克莱普顿
"Sorry about the buckle rash. Eric Clapton."
谢谢  这太漂亮了
Thank you. This is beautiful.
他干吗这么做
Why is he doing this?
当自己8岁吗
What is he, like eight years old?
给  亲爱的
Here, honey.
谢谢
Thanks.
这是沃尔特送的
Oh, this is from Walt.
-天哪  -没事
- God. - It's okay!
方便面
Yum-good ramen.
为了写论文
This is what Walt and I...
我和沃尔特两人
Lived on for 10 months straight
10个月赖以生存的东西
While we were working on our thesis.
在五金店旁边那个商店有卖
They sold them down at Ralsto's in the hardware aisle,
就在  那什么旁边来着
Right next to the... the what was it?
-斯特诺  -斯特诺旁边
- Sterno.  - The Sterno.
10包才1.99美金
Yeah, 10 for $1.99.
至今我已然确信
To this day, I am convinced
这些面条是我们不可或缺的助力
These noodles were responsible for our success.
这是我们的生命之源
This was our lifeblood.
你在哪里找到的
Where'd you find these?
我以为多年前就成非法产品了
I thought they'd been outlawed years ago.
我喜欢
I love it.
谢谢你  沃尔特
Thank you, Walt.
送给拥有一切的人
For the man who has everything.
-不  不  -就是
- No, no. - It was.
你记得那个胖子吗
You remember the fat guy, the fat guy.
我们以前叫他鼻涕虫的胖子
We used to call him "snot trough"
因为他老是挂着...
Because he had that thing under his n...
-什么来着  -那是多普金斯
- What do you call that thing? - That was Dobkins!
和那个一天到晚闻起来
That was the same guy who always
巨臭无比的是同一个人
Smelled like chocked nose.
-就是  -不  不是
- It was!  - No, no, no, no.
那个不是多普金斯
It wasn't Dobkins. It was...
我发誓  因为那人老是穿
Anyway, I swear to Christ he used to iron those patches
在手肘那里有块补丁的外套
Onto the elbows of his members only jacket because
他觉得那样很有型
He thought it made him look more distinguished.
-你觉得他有型么  -不
- Didn't it?  - No.
-敬鼻涕虫  -敬鼻涕虫
- Well, here's to snot trough. - To snot trough.
-不论他在哪里  -上帝保佑你
- Wherever you may be. - God bless him.
你还记得那个讨厌
And you remember the professor
罗伯特·威廉·本生的教授么
Who used to hate Robert Wilhelm Bunsen?
恩
Yes.
你只要一提到那个名字
All you had to do was mention the Bunsen Burner
他就会发飙
And he was off on a rant.
"他根本没发明这个"  还记得他老挥手么
"No, he didn't invent it." You remember the waving?
"他不过是证明了而已"
"He just improved it!" you know.
瞬间就能少上15分钟课
It was easy to kill 15 minutes anyway.
我真怀念我们之间这样的对话  沃尔特
Oh god, I miss this, Walt.
我也是
Yeah. Me, too.
我们应该一起多聚聚
Listen, we ought to get together more often.
斯凯勒和我非常欢迎你和格蕾琴
Skyler and I would love to have you and
来我们家吃晚饭
Gretchen over for dinner sometime.
恩  当然
Sure, yeah, absolutely.
但我的意思是
But what I mean is
我们应该再次合作
That you and I should work together again.
-你来高中上课么  -说真的
- Are you going to teach high school? - No, no. Seriously.
之前有什么阻止我们么
What's stopping us?
等等  埃利奥特  你是说
Wait a minute. Elliott, what are you...
要我去格雷麦特工作么
Are you asking me to come work for you at Gray Matter?
对啊  你很合适啊
Yeah. Why not? You'd fit right in.
你很有才气而且经验丰富
You're brilliant, you've got a ton of experience.
我...
Well, I...
我不知道怎么开始
I wouldn't really know where to begin. I mean...
你根本不了解
God. You have no idea.
我一天到晚就在黑板前
I spend my days just drawing out atoms on the chalkboard
试图让学生们学会元素周期表
And trying to get these kids to learn the periodic table.
我了解
Look, I understand.
你是有点点生疏
You're a little rusty, but you're
但你没看到好处
Not seeing the upside here...
你带来的新角度对我们非常有帮助
We could really benefit from a new set of eyes.
你知道吧
You know what it is when you been
当你花费几个月破解一个难题
Trying to crack some problem for months on end.
你的视角就会变得狭窄
You get tunnel vision.
正所谓旁观者清
One guy thinking outside of the box...
你恰恰是我们所需要的
You may be exactly what we need.
埃利奥特
Well, listen, Elliott...
你的提议很动人
Your offer is very appealing.
真的  谢谢
It really is. Thank you.
但有些事你要知道
There's something you should know.
我有些...
I have some...
个人事务
Personal issues.
没有什么不能解决的
Look, there's nothing we can't work out.
但是这有点复杂
Well, yeah, but it's complicated.
我们能帮助你
We can help you.
我们有很好的医疗保险
We have excellent health insurance.
最好的
The best.
你试过他们的
Hey, did you try those prosciutto wrapped figs?
意大利熏火腿没
They were like...wow.
太好吃  我大概吃了有30个
They were just... I must have had about 30 of those suckers.
还有海鲜桌  你看到没
And the seafood table. Did you see that?
有龙虾尾  蟹钳  虾
They had lobster tail, they had crab legs, shrimp.
你TM都对埃利奥特说什么了
What the hell did you say to Elliott?
你跟他说了我的癌症  对吧
You told him about the cancer, didn't you?
对吧
Didn't you?
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
好吧  我们是聊了一会儿
Okay, we were talking.
他问我关于你的情况  我很抱歉
He asked how you were doing, and I am sorry,
这阵子我可做不到喜怒不形于色
But I don't have the best poker face these days
特别是说到关键问题时候
Where that's concerned.
他知道你不对劲  是他追问我的
He knew something was wrong with you and he pressed me.
他追问你吗  简直胡说
He pressed you. Come on.
沃尔特
Walt!
在这个问题上
When it came right down to it,
我不知道除了告诉他事实外还能做什么
I didn't know what else to do but tell him the truth.
事实  你干嘛不直接就说他很好
The truth? How about you just said "he's fine," huh?
如果你就跟他说
You think maybe you could've just have said that
他很好  不就完了吗
"He's fine," and that would be done.
我不喜欢你这种说话的态度
I don't like the way you're talking to me.
我不喜欢你跟别人说我的私事
I don't like the way you talk about my private affairs
跟那些已经远离我们生活的人说
To people who are not even in our lives anymore.
你到底跟他说了什么
What exactly did he say to you?
他想给我个工作
He offered me a job.
-什么  -就是那样
- What? - Yes.
就像块遮羞布  知道吗
Kind of like some fig leaf, you know?
想要保全我的面子
Some face-saving bullshit
好让我大方  接受他对我的施舍
That allowed me to generously accept his charity.
我拒绝他以后
And then, when I turned that down,
他就直接说愿意帮我付治疗费用
He flat-out offered to pay for my treatment.
这就是你想让他做的  不是吗
Which is exactly what you expected him to do, didn't you?
-不是吗  -沃尔特  不是
- Didn't you?  - Walt. No.
-你就承认吧  -我没有让他
- Please. Come on. - I did not put him up...
好吧  那你说了什么
Okay, what did you say?
沃尔特
Walt?
你认为我会说什么
What do you think I said?
为什么  沃尔特
Why? Walt...
-准备走了吗  -我去乘公车
- You ready to go? - I'm taking the bus.
好的
Okay...
拜拜  亲爱的
Bye, honey.
嘿  伙计  这些是弹孔吗
Hey, dude, are these bullet holes?
不是  这些是用来
No, man. Those are for, like, you know,
通气的
Ventilation.
真酷啊
Cool.
不错的装备啊
Nice set-up, huh?
这没什么
This is nothing, man.
我以前有这两倍多的玻璃器皿
I used to have, like, twice as much glassware
直到我那以前的蠢货搭档把车开进了沟里
Until my dumbass ex-partner drove us into a ditch
多数都打破了
And wrecked most of it.
大号烧杯
Big ass beaker, huh?
等一下  不  这是个大号烧瓶
Wait, wait. No, that's a... yeah, that's a boiling flask.
这个才是烧杯
This is a beaker.
这是格里芬烧杯  这是容量瓶
Here's a griffin beaker, here's a volumetric beaker.
这是爱伦美氏锥形瓶
Here's an erlenmeyer flask.
哇  你懂得可真多
Wow. You really know your shit.
这些知识化学基本常识  哟
Well, it's just basic chemistry, yo.
你带东西来了吗
So... you got something for me?
哦 当然
Oh, hells, yeah!
好的  我们要开工了
Okay. We're in business.
-太好了  猴子  -伙计  看看这个
- Right on, Badger. - Dude, check this out.
老天啊  你带那个来干嘛
Jesus, what the hell are you bringing that for?
打猎
Hunting.
我们可能会碰到野猪
We might see javelinas.
你到底要不要帮忙
Are you going to help me or what?
猴子
Badger!
给我点钱
Let me see the money.
一人5块  快点  再来两张
Nah, I need five each. Come on, two more.
给
Here.
他怎么样
What about him?
你在开玩笑吗  他看起来比我们小
Are you kidding? He looks younger than us.
随你的便
Whatever.
那个怎么样
What about that guy?
-他看上去像是做生意的  -那又怎么样
- Nah, he looks like a businessman. - So what?
生意人老是匆匆忙忙的
So, businessmen are always in a hurry.
他们好像一天到晚要去开会什么的
They're always, like, going to some meeting or something.
说真的  他肯定会拒绝
Seriously, he's just going to say no.
那个人
This guy.
就是他了
This is our guy.
你去
You're up.
为什么非让我去
Why do I have to do it?
你把拐杖给我  我就去
Give me the crutches and I'll go do it.
打扰一下
Excuse me, hey.
我们忘带身份证了  想问一下
We forgot our IDs and we were wondering
你能不能帮我们买一扎啤酒
If you could do us a favor and buy us a six-pack.
知道吗  你的要求违法
You know, what you're asking is illegal.
不  不违法
No, it's not?
它确实是
Yeah, it is.
哦  见鬼
Oh, shit.
我猜你中头奖了
Guess you win the jackpot.
我可不想就这样浪费我空闲的晚上
This is not how I wanted to spend my night off.
记住这是对你第一次也是最后一次警告
Consider this your first and last warning.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
你很幸运有这么好的老爸
You're lucky you got a good dad here.
如果其他人不跑的话
If the other guys hadn't run,
我早就没事了
I could've talked my way out of it.
这么做太不明智了  不明智
Not cool, man. Not cool.
怎么  你像我这么大时没试过买啤酒吗
What, you never tried to buy beer when you were my age?
不  我是说你打电话给我而不是你老爸
No, I'm talking about you calling me and not your father.
你觉得他会怎么想
How do you think that will make him feel?
我都不知道要说你什么好
I don't even know what to say to you.
快点走开
Just go.
待会儿找你算账
I'll deal with you later.
沃尔特去哪了
Where's Walt?
我从早上就没见过他
I haven't seen him since this morning.
知道的跟你差不多
Your guess is as good as mine.
帮我个忙  好吗
Listen, do me a favor, all right?
别告诉他孩子的事
Don't tell him about the kid.
不过是小孩子想买点啤酒罢了
Just a teenager trying to score some beer.
成长的烦恼
You know. Just growing pains.
他发现自己的老爸病了
I mean, he finds out his dad's sick,
他想找点法子解脱
He starts acting out, you know.
先是大麻  现在又是这个
First the pot, and then this.
什么大麻
The pot?
你跟我说他抽大麻的
You told me he was smoking reefer.
是斯凯勒告诉我的
That's what's Skyler told me.
我是说  你就是这么暗示的
I mean, you may as well have.
我说的不是小沃尔特
I wasn't talking about Walter Jr.
我说的是沃尔特
I was talking about Walt.
你说什么
Excuse me?
他亲口承认的
He admitted it.
他说他喜欢
He said he liked it.
沃尔特
Walt?
我以为他不是那种人
I didn't think he had it in him.
最近他变了很多
It's like he's not himself lately.
有哪个神经正常的人
I mean, why would anyone in their right mind
会选择不接受治疗
Choose not to do treatment?
而且还有人愿意出所有的费用
Especially when it's completely paid for?
他为什么这么做
Why is he doing this?
知道我们该怎么做吗
You know what we need to do?
我们真正该做的是要让他坐下来
What we really need to do is sit him down, all of us,
开诚布公地跟他谈
And get everything out on the table.
好好地谈一谈
Talk it all through.
你是指我们来干扰他吗
You mean an intervention?
不是不是
No, no.
只是个家庭会议
Just a family meeting...
每个家庭成员都可以发表
Where everyone can voice their concerns and...
自己的意见
Be heard.
你太有才了  老兄
You are a genius, bro!
这次的成品太完美了
This cankenstein is unreal!
我们回去后就把美钞电版[假钞模具]毁掉
When we get back, I'm gonna burn that dollar bill suit.
我们可要发大财了
'Cause we're gonna make some mad dough!
不对
It's not right.
什么不对  你什么意思
What do you mean it's not right?
看上去很浑浊
It's... cloudy.
不应该是浑浊的样子
It's not supposed to be cloudy.
上次  是透明的
That last time, it was glass.
那又怎样
So what?
不管浑不浑浊  对我来说足够了
Cloudy, not cloudy, it looks good enough to me.
足够了
"Good enough."
喂  你干嘛啊
Yo, what are you doing?
你脑子进水了是吧  我还准备好好享用的呢
Are you out of your mind?  I totally would've smoked that!
不是给你的  是给我们客户的
Look, it's not for you, it's for our customers.
他们对成色有一定要求
They're gonna demand a certain standard.
什么
What?
你到底  什么
What are you... what?
我们再做一次
We'll just do it again...
直到合乎要求
Until we get it right.
沃尔特
Walt...
请坐  我们来谈谈
Please have a seat and join us.
还可以做得更纯
We can do better.
你TMD别做梦了
Don't you fucking think about it!
整整3磅假麻黄素就被你浪费了
Three entire pounds of pseudo wasted!
你知不知道我套着那个标志转了多久
You know how long I had to spin that stupid sign?
离我远点  神经病
Get off me, psycho!
又来这招  婊子
Helicopter, bitch!
混蛋
Asshole
开门
Open the door!
回来  你这婊子
Come back here, you bitch!
我要整死你
I'm gonna mess you up!
我真的要好好理解一下的你的想法
I really need to understand your thought
但很明显我不明白
Process because clearly I don't.
我感觉
I feel
你做的这个决定
That this decision you've made
不仅于你无益
Is not only not in your best interest,
而且有悖于我们整个家庭
It's not in the best interest of our entire family.
-听我说  斯凯勒  -我还没说完
- Look, Skyler... - Not yet. please.
我有一个发言枕
I have the talking pillow.
每个人都可以倾吐心声  记得吗
Everybody gets to speak their minds, remember?
接下来  该你了
And then, you'll get your chance.
钱对于我们来说总是个问题  我先声明
Money has always been an issue for us, I'll give you that.
但现在埃利奥特非常愿意帮我们忙
But now that Elliott is more than willing to pitch in,
我很清楚  你不怎么愿意接受帮助
I know, I understand that it's hard for you to accept help.
可能你一直就是这种性格
Maybe it's the way you were raised.
但是  亲爱的
But, honey...
偶尔依靠他人没什么不对的
It's okay to lean on people now and again.
你需要治疗
You need this treatment,
除了你自己
And nothing can stop you from getting it,
没有任何事阻止得了这个
Except you.
我可以答话吗
May I allowed to respond?
等一等
In a minute.
我们先轮着发言
I think we need to go around the circle first.
汉克  你开头好吗
Hank, would you like to start?
好的  行
Yeah. Okay.
-我要说的是  -等等  拿着发言枕
- Well, what I'll say is... - No, take the talking pillow.
是这样  听着  兄弟
All right, look, buddy.
我知道我说的话也许没什么分量  但是
I know I don't get to tell you this enough, but...
我很关心  很关心你
I care... about you...
非常非常关心
A hell of a lot.
这个癌症
This cancer thing...
我们  我们勇敢面对它吧
Let's just... let's face it.
你的遭遇确实很不幸
You know, you were dealt a shit hand.
但是
But...
运气也会改变的嘛
Sometimes your luck can change.
我是说  我都不知道讲了几遍了
I mean, I can't tell you how many times I was, you know,
我从当初一无所有  到现在的美满生活
I started with a shit hand and I ended up with a full house.
明白吗
Okay?
我是说  关键就在于  你要坚强
I mean, the key is, you gotta hang in there.
兄弟  你要心怀希望
Man, you gotta keep placing your bets.
要心怀希望
Keep placing your bets.
汉克  你说的什么乱七八糟的
Hank... What the hell are you saying?
玛丽  让他说  我们就是来沟通的
Please, Marie, let him talk. That's what we're here to do.
让他说
Please.
继续吧  汉克
Go on, Hank.
好的
Right, well...
我们这么想问题  好吗
Look at it this way, okay?
打一场九局棒球赛  满垒了
It's the bottom of the 9th. Bases are loaded.
该你上场
You're up.
但是你的胳膊有毛病
But you got a bum arm. Right?
你根本没可能击出一个本垒打
There's no frickin' way you're gonna hit a homer, okay?
所以你要么让替补球员替你
So you can either let the pinch hitter take the bat,
或者坚持下去  有尊严的输掉比赛
Or you can hold on to your pride and lose the game.
明白我说的了吗
Get what I'm saying?
没
No.
你想活出尊严来  这个我理解  兄弟
You got your pride, man. I get it. Okay?  I get it.
要是沃巴克斯老爹要出钱的话
If this Daddy Warbucks wants to chip in, man,
我就赞同你老婆
I'm with your old lady on this one.
拿了钱就拍屁股走人
I say take the money and run, you know.
有人要拿这东西吗  给
Somebody want to take this thing?  Here.
嗯  沃尔特
Yes, Walter...
小沃尔特  你肯定
Walter Junior., I'm sure you have about
有一肚子话要说  也许吧  现在给你机会
A million things to say, probably, and now is your chance.
说吧  都说出来
Go ahead. just let it all out.
-全是扯蛋  -拜托
- This is bullshit. - Hey, come on.
没事的
It's all right.
讲啊
Talk.
告诉爸爸你的感受
Tell your Dad how you feel.
-烦着呢  -告诉他
- I'm pissed off. - Tell him.
我烦得要死
I'm pissed off,
因为你就
'Cause you're being...
你就像
You're...
就像个懦夫
You're a pussy.
你看上去像是  准备好了放弃
You're, like, ready to give up.
天  你要是也放弃我怎么办
God. What if you gave up on me, huh?
看这个  我都经历过这么多
This here?  All the stuff I've been through,
而你却怕那小儿科的化疗
And you're scared of a little chemotherapy?
我  个人立场
Me, personally
我认为应该由你自己来选择
I think you should do whatever you want to do.
什么
What?
你说过我们要诚实的表达心里的想法
You told us to be honest about our feelings.
是沃尔特得了癌症  就该由他自己决断
Walt's the one with cancer. It's his decision.
我们任何人都不能喧宾夺主
It's not up to any of us.
你为什么要搞鬼乱来
Why in the hell would you do this?
我并不是一直打算要袒护沃尔特
I wasn't planning on agreeing with Walt.
但是坐在这听你们说了这么久
But after sitting here and listening to you all
谈论他的将来  像是他没有发言权似的
Talk about his future like he has no say in it.
要是他不去治病
He's not gonna have a future
他就不会有将来
If he doesn't get treatment.
我可是专业医疗人员
I am a medical professional.
我每天给治疗中的病人照X光
I X-Ray people in treatment every day.
我每天都见到他们  你知道吗
I see them every day, and you know what?
有些人真的是非常的痛苦
Some of them are absolutely miserable.
-玛丽   -对不起  但这是事实
- Marie...  - I'm sorry, but it's true.
有些人并不愿意
And some of them don't wanna spend
将他们最后的日子
Their last weeks or months
无味地跟医生消磨耗尽
Being picked at by doctors.
而他们都是被家人劝说进医院的
But they got talked into it by their families.
能把发言枕还我吗  我同意玛丽的话
Could I get the pillow back? I agree with Marie on that.
-汉克  -什么  也许沃尔特想死得其所
- Hank - What? Maybe Walt wants to die like a man.
可我不想让他死
I don't want him to die at all!
这才是关键问题  要么帮忙要么走人
That's the whole point of this. So either help, or leave!
斯凯勒  我只是好意地
Skyler, I just wanted to do you the courtesy
告诉你我的真实想法
Of giving you my honest opinion.
玛丽  这又不是辩论会
You know, Marie, this is not debate club.
这是我丈夫的命
This is my husband's life.
我做个简单的观察
I make one simple observation...
-我丈夫的命  -我们正在讨论这事
- My husband's life - We're talking about!
-女士们  别吵了  -你怎么能
- Ladies. come on. - How dare you...
这太蠢了
This is so stupid.
行了  我现在拿到发言枕了
All right, I've got the talking pillow now.
好了吗
Okay?
在坐的各位
We all, in this room,
我们都深爱着彼此
We love each other.
我们希望对彼此都好的决定  我也明白
We want what's best for each other, and I know that.
我非常感激你们
I am very thankful for that.
可是
But...
我想要的
What I want...
我所想的  我所要的
What I want, what I need,
是一次选择
Is a choice.
那是什么意思
What does that... mean?
有时候  我觉得自己从没有
Sometimes, I feel like I never actually
为我自己而活
Make any of my own.
选择  我的意思是
Choices, I mean.
我这一生
My entire life,
似乎从未
It just seems I never...
真正选择过
You know, had a kind of real say about any of it.
现在最后的选择来了  癌症
Now this last one, cancer...
我唯一能做的选择是如何面对癌症
All I have left is how I choose to approach this.
沃尔特  那就做个正确的选择
Then make the right choice, Walt.
你不是唯一得癌症的人
You're not the only one it affects.
你的儿子怎么办
What about your son?
你不想看着你女儿长大成人吗  我只是
Don't you wanna see your daughter grow up? I just...
当然  我当然想
Of course, I do.
斯凯勒  你也看过统计数据了
Skyler, you've read the statistics.
那些医生们
These doctors...
讨论着我还能活的时间
Talking about surviving.
一年还是两年
One year, two years,
就好像这是唯一重要的事一样
Like it's the only thing that matters.
而活着又能怎样呢  仅仅是活着
But what good is it, to just survive
要是我病得不能工作
If I am too sick to work,
不能享受美食
To enjoy a meal,
不能做爱
To make love?
我想在我剩下的日子里
For what time I have left,
住在自己的家里
I want to live in my own house.
睡在自己的床上
I want to sleep in my own bed.
我不想每天咽下30还是40片药
I don't wanna choke down 30 or 40 pills every single day,
又是脱发  到处掩饰
Lose my hair, and lie around,
又是卧床不起
Too tired to get up...
反胃得连脑袋都不能动
And so nauseated that I can't even move my head.
你就成天守在榻前伺候我吗
And you cleaning up after me?
我
Me, with...
和死人  和靠人工维持生命的人
Some dead man, some artificially alive,
有什么区别
Just marking time?
不  不
No. No.
而你就会记得那样的我
And that's how you would remember me.
这是我最不愿意的
That's the worst part.
那么
So...
斯凯勒  这就是我所考虑的
That is my thought process, Skyler.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是
I just...
我选择顺其自然
I choose not to do it.
好吧
All right.
什么好吧
All right what?
我会接受治疗
I'll do the treatment.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
账单室的女士说
The lady from the billing office said
他们一般直接给保险公司开账单
They usually bill the insurance company directly,
不过  既然我们的医疗保险不付钱
But since our HMO is not paying for it,
我们可以用信用卡付
We can pay up front with a credit card.
好
Good.
埃利奥特会寄张支票来
And then Elliott will send a check.
我会处理好的
I will take care of it.
沃尔特·怀特
Walter White?
是我
Yes.
好
Okay.
一会儿见
See you in a minute.
埃利奥特
Elliott.
沃尔特  我是格蕾琴
Walt, it's Gretchen.
你好
Oh, hey.
格蕾琴  你还好吗
Hey, Gretchen. How are you?
那天见到你们可真高兴
You know, it was really great seeing you two the other day.
多令人高兴的聚会
What a party.
埃利奥特跟我说了癌症的事
Elliott told me about the cancer.
我非常遗憾
I'm so sorry.
你知道  也就是那样了
Well, you know, it is what it is, I guess.
我会永远支持你
I don't know what to say except
除了这个我也不知道该说什么
I'm always here for you.
我们都  我们都想对你说这句话
Both of us are. We wanted you to know that.
谢谢
Yeah, well, thank you.
埃利奥特跟我说了
Walt, Elliott's told me
他要支付治疗费用
He had offered to pay for the treatment.
你一定要接受
You have to accept.
那笔钱  出自我们的关心
That money, as far as we're both concerned,
它是属于你的
That belongs to you.
甚至我们公司的名字  都有一半是你的
Even the name of our company, it's half yours.
沃尔特
Walt...
你和我就这样了吗
Is this about you and me?
格蕾琴  我很感谢你们的好意  真的
Gretchen, I really appreciate the offer. I do.
但是我们能挺过去
But we're fine.
结果是保险公司会支付那些钱的
As it turns out, the insurance came through after all.
所以  我在保障范围内
So... I am covered.
无论如何  非常感谢   谢谢你
Well, anyway, I really appreciate it. Thank you.
是吗  这是个好消息
Good, that's good news.
那真是个盛大的聚会
You know, that really was a great party.
常联系  好吗
Keep in touch, okay?
当然  当然
Sure. sure.
谢谢你的来电
Thank you for calling.
要制毒吗
You wanna cook?